BUT I MUST
EXPLAIN TO
YOU HOW
ALL THIS
MISTAKEN
IDEA OF
DENOUNCING
PLEASURE
AND
PRAISING
PAIN WAS
BORN AND I
WILL GIVE
YOU A
COMPLETE
ACCOUNT OF
THE
SYSTEM.
AND
EXPOUND
THE ACTUAL
TEACHINGS
OF THE
GREAT
EXPLORER
OF THE
TRUTH, THE
MASTER
BUILDER OF
HUMAN
HAPPINESS,
NO ONE
REJECTS,
DISLIKES
OR AVOIDS.
PLEASURE
ITSELF,
BECAUSE IT
IS
PLEASURE,
BUT
BECAUSE
THOSE WHO
DO NOT
KNOW HOW
TO PURSUE
PLEASURE
RATIONALLY
ENCOUNTER
CONSEQUENCES
THAT ARE
EXTREMELY
PAINFUL.
NOR AGAIN,
IS THERE
ANYONE WHO
LOVES OR
PURSUES OR
DESIRES TO
OBTAIN
PAIN OF
ITSELF
BECAUSE IT
IS PAIN,
BUT
BECAUSE
OCCASIONALLY
CIRCUMSTANCE
SEES OCCUR
IN WHICH
TOIL AND
PAIN CAN
PROCURE
HIM SOME
GREAT
PLEASURE.
TO TAKE A
TRIVIAL
EXAMPLE,
WHICH OF
US EVER
UNDERTAKES
LABORIOUS
PHYSICAL
EXERCISE
EXCEPT TO
OBTAIN
SOME
ADVANTAGE
FROM IT.
BUT WHO
HAS ANY
RIGHT TO
FIND FAULT
WITH A MAN
WHO
CHOOSES TO
ENJOY A
PLEASURE
THAT HAS
NO
ANNOYANCE,
QUENCERS,
OR ONE WHO
AVOIDS A
PAIN THAT
PRODUCES
NO
RESULTANT
PLEASURE.